

Applicant for:

Senior Java Engineer ~2,000\$ (SL: 05)

Dr.JOY 1 March 2021

Dau Dinh

□ peterlee2068@gmail.com

What skills, work projects or achievements make you a strong candidate for this position?

I'm Dau Dinh, Currently, I'm a Senior Backend Software Engineer at LINE Technology VN with

over 10 years of experience. I've had a lot of knowledge about Software Design Principles,

Design Patterns, and Database Design. Besides, I've also deep knowledge about Java (concurrency & parallelism, memory management, and so on) and Python languages. I really

fall in love with system design. In my free time, I often study and learn to design largescale

systems in LINE and the internet.

CURRICULUM VITAE

NAME	DINH MANH DAU
ROLE	Senior Backend Software Engineer

OVERVIEW

Personal

- Date Of Birth: December 11th, 1988

Full Name: Dinh Manh DauSkype: dinh.manh.dau

- Email: dinhmanhdau@gmail.com

- Phone: 84398698909

Blog: https://medium.com/@peterlee2068

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/dau-dinh/

Summary

I'm Dau Dinh, Currently, I'm a Senior Backend Software Engineer at LINE Technology VN with over 10 years of experience. I've had a lot of knowledge about Software Design Principles, Design Patterns, and Database Design. Besides, I've also deep knowledge about Java (concurrency & parallelism, memory management, and so on) and Python languages. I really fall in love with system design. In my free time, I often study and learn to design large-scale systems in LINE and the internet.

Learning new languages and technologies is what I am passionate about. I can work as a technical leader because I like to help others and tend to work well within groups. I can also do some mentoring tasks and do code review for other team members.

ACHIVEMENTS	
Joined TechTalk#38, 2020	Role: Speaker Topic: Redis best practices Event: TechTalk #38 - Languages, Technologies, Architectures Organized by LINE Technology VN and Grokking Vietnam

EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS	
Graduated from	National University of Civil Engineering
Graduated year	2011
Major	Software Engineering Department
Degree	Good

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY		
Period	Company	Position
October, 2010 – February, 2011	Vietsoftware International	Internship
March, 2011 - March, 2014	ManaTech	Developer
April, 2014 – September, 2017	Adways Vietnam	Senior Developer
October, 2017 – now	LINE Vietnam	Senior Software Engineer

SKILLS

Programming languages

- Java
- Python
- Kotlin
- PHP
- NodeJS
- JavaScript
- HTML, CSS

Frameworks & platforms

- Spring Framework
- Laravel, Symfony, CakePHP, Yii 2
- Django
- Scrapy
- VueJS

Database

- MySQL
- Redis
- MongoDB

Search engine

- SphinX
- ElasticSearch
- Solr

IDE

- Visual Studio Code
- IntelliJ
- Sublime Text

Version Control

- Git
- Svn

Issue tracking tool

- Jira
- Redmine

Continuous Integration tool

- CircleCl
- Jenkins

Foreign Language

- English

Knowledge

- Deep understanding about OOP, Design Pattern, SOLID principles, Dependency Injection
- Good understanding about the Agile and Scrum process
- Good understanding software design, database design
- Good time management and teamwork skills

WORKING EXPER	WORKING EXPERIENCE	
1. Project	GPS Ship Tracking	
Company	Vietsoftware International	
Duration	October, 2010 - February, 2011	
Position	Internship	
Description	Support end-user to search ship's position, name's ship, and other ship around the current position in the map.	
Responsibility	- Research and develop iOS application	
Technology	- Database: SQLite - Language: Objective C	

2. Project	ManaPortal
Company	ManaTech
Duration	March, 2011 - May, 2013
Position	Developer
Description	 The information portal includes news from 70 top papers in Vietnam. News: culture, social, sport, entertainment, story, image, video, horoscope, Support offline mode Support device J2ME, Android, iOS Total user uses ManaPortal: > 1.600.000 users.
Responsibility	 Implement server-side and client side (J2ME and Android application) Review source code, design and unit test. Manage server Linux (including config, build and deploy applications) Crawler and process news
Technology	 Java Socket Frameworks: Simple MVC Database: MongoDB (Master-slave, Delicate server, VPS,) and MySQL Cache: Redis & Memcached Languages: Java/PHP/Python

3. Project	OpAlarm
Company	ManaTech
Duration	June, 2013 - December, 2013
Position	Developer
Description	OpAlarm (Start Up: TOPICA Founder Showcase) is a service help user to follow, research information in electronic commerce site and forum easily. The suitable information will be OpAlarm notice to users via email or SMS at the moment.
Responsibility	 Implement server-side Implement client-side (Android application) Manage server Linux (including config, build and deploy applications)
Technology	Languages: Java/PHPDatabase: MySQL

4. Project	Yton
Company	ManaTech
Duration	December, 2013 - March, 2014
Position	Developer
Description	Yton is an application allow user used to read the news of medical, research knowledge, notice calendar helps pregnant women.
Responsibility	 Implement server-side Implement client-side (Android application) Manage server Linux (including config, build and deploy applications)
Technology	- Languages: Java/PHP - Database: MySQL

5. Project	Drawsomething
Company	Adways Vietnam
Duration	April, 2014 - September, 2014
Position	Senior Developer
Description	 Drawsomething is a game for the user to draw and guess the keyword Integrate Facebook, Twitter, Line SDK framework
Responsibility	 Analysis and design features Implement server-side Implement client-side(Android application) Review code and detail design
Technology	Languages: Java/PHPDatabase: MySQLFramework: CakePHP

6. Project	Bengo4 & Zeiri4
Company	Adways Vietnam
Duration	December, 2013 - March, 2014
Position	Senior Developer
Description	Bengo4 & Zeiri4 is a top site about the lawyer of Japan. It is an information portal between lawyer and end-user, help end-user connect with the lawyer.
Responsibility	 Analysis and design features Implement server-side Manage server Linux (including config, build and deploy applications) Review code and detail design
Technology	Languages: Java/PHPDatabase: MySQLFramework: Yii2

7. Project	Giftpoint
Company	Adways Vietnam
Duration	April, 2014 - March, 2015
Position	Senior Developer
Description	Provide service making money via mobile phone (android, iOS) by install campaign application in many countries such as Vietnam, Thailand, Indo, When end-user install application, they will receive point and can exchange point to card mobile (Viettel, Mobifone, Vinaphone). End-user can use their point to bet football match.
Responsibility	 Analysis and design features Implement server-side Review detail design and code Manage server Linux on AWS (including config, build and deploy applications)
Technology	Languages: PHPFramework: CakePHP, Laravel, SymfonyDatabase: MySQL

8. Project	VideoTool
Company	Adways Vietnam
Duration	July, 2016 - September, 2017
Position	Senior Developer
Description	VideoTool a video creation tool that supports companies to generate a large number of creatives.
Responsibility	 Analysis and design features Implement server-side Implement client-side (desktop application) Review code and detail design
Technology	Languages: Java/PHPFramework: JavaFX, LaravelDatabase: MySQL

9. Project	Charmmy
Company	LINE Vietnam
Duration	October, 2017 – March, 2018
Position	Senior Software Engineer
Description	Charmmy is an application of LINE, provide fortunes for user, special woman. The content of fortune is described in detail in articles in different category, by writer. User can pay cost for it by LINE account.
Responsibility	 Analysis and design features Implement Backend API Implement Admin Tool Review code and detail design Manage server Linux (including config, build and deploy applications)
Technology	 Languages: Java Framework: Spring MVC/JPA Database: MySQL Search engine: Elasticsearch Cache: Redis Message Queue: RabbitMQ

10. Project	LINE Consult Portal
Company	LINE Vietnam
Duration	April, 2018 – June, 2018
Position	Senior Software Engineer
Description	This is consult portal for LINE. Promote service of LINE: Talk care, talk fortune,
Responsibility	 Analysis and design features Implement server-side (Backend API) Implement front-end Manage server Linux (including config, build and deploy applications)
Technology	 Languages: Java Framework: Spring (JPA) Database: MySQL Cache: Redis

11. Project	Line@
Company	LINE Vietnam
Duration	July, 2018 – Aug, 2019
Position	Senior Software Engineer
Description	Line@ is a special application for the company, shop, and organization.
	It has a wide range of features enables you to promote your company, brand, or product in new and far-reaching ways.
Responsibility	 Analysis and design features Implement client-side Config, build and deploy application via CI/CD Review code and detail design
Technology	- Languages: Javascript - Framework: VueJS

12. Project	Lineman: Taxi web service
Company	LINE Vietnam
Duration	Sep, 2019 – Oct, 2019
Position	Senior Software Engineer
Description	Like Grab, Lineman is the product of LINE includes many services: food delivery, Parcel, Taxi,
	Taxi web service helps staff book multi-trips for a customer in hotels, hospitals, office buildings, soccer fields via the website.
Responsibility	 Analysis and design features Config, build and deploy application via CI/CD Review code and detail design
Technology	Languages: JavaFramework: Spring (JPA)Database: MongoDB 3.6Caching: Redis

13. Project	Line News
Company	LINE Vietnam
Duration	Nov, 2019 – Dec, 2020
Position	Senior Software Engineer
Description	Line News is an application for reading news. From important topics to entertainment!
	Users can easily receive selected news every day.
	The editorial department carefully selects articles from a wide range of genres: Fashion from national newspapers, business magazines, sports magazines.
	Weather, route information, earthquake bulletins will be delivered as soon as possible.
Responsibility	 Analysis and design features Config, build and deploy application via PMC, CI/CD Review code and detail design
Technology	 Languages: Java/Kotlin Framework: Spring(JPA, Mybatis) Database: MySQL v5.7/MongoDB v3.6 Caching: Redis

14. Project	Line Bot
Company	LINE Vietnam
Duration	March, 2020 - now
Position	Senior Software Engineer
Description	Line bot is including a lot of bots:
	 Weather bot for Japan, Korea, Thailand, Indonesia, and Taiwan countries: provides the weather information of the present day of the region that the user has input. In addition, send push weather information when user setting receive push from system.
	 Disaster alert bot: when earthquake comes, sending alert messages to users with the location and scale of it. It also provides covid19 information.
	 Fortune bot: sending daily fortune message based on user's birthday setting.
	- Lotto bot: sending weekly message with winning numbers of lotto.
Responsibility	 Analysis and design features Config, build and deploy application via PMC Review code and detail design

	- Support/guide Junior
Technology	 Languages: Java/Kotlin Framework: Spring (JPA, Mybatis) Database: MySQL v5.7 Message Queue: RabbitMQ, Kafka Caching: Redis